# **Sujay Vittal**

Developer Associate at SAP Labs India Pvt. Ltd.

# Summary

I am a careful and creative thinker with an eye for details and a devotion to logic, which serves me well both in the sciences and outside them. I have a terrific ability to draw on my own experience and observations to develop thoughtful opinions on a variety of issues.

I am looking out for challenging opportunities in the technical / non-technical fields of employment to make myself be better at what I do and contribute as much as possible to the betterment of the company I am associated with.

With a variety of experience in Entrepreneurship, Software Development, Digital Marketing, Designing, Facilitating programs, Leading teams, I feel I am capable of handling challenges and I enjoy when an opportunity that is something new and more challenging than the previous one is thrown at me. For better insights into the different areas of experience I've had, feel free to visit my site (www.sujayvittal.com).

I love making new professional acquaintances. Reach out if you want to talk Technology, Music, Business or Cricket.

# Experience

#### **Developer Associate at SAP Labs**

August 2016 - Present (8 months)

Currently working on the Platform Search Service of SAP BusinessObjects Business Intelligence Platform (BIP).

# Facilitator - Applied CS with Android at Google

March 2016 - December 2016 (10 months)

Responsible for training undergrad freshmen/seniors with basic computer science skills using Android as a platform

#### Software Developer Intern at SAP Ariba

January 2016 - July 2016 (7 months)

Was responsible to work on a tool that involved writing Pig Scripts to analyze some of the transactions that were happening. Also, with this task I was expected to build a mock up of a node which would help the testing team test the latest builds efficiently.

#### Team Lead and Member Technical Staff at Ordell Ugo

#### April 2013 - May 2016 (3 years 2 months)

Biological Congruence - [First year of Engineering - Summer '13] This was the project for which I was heading a team of 3 during my first year of engineering at a on-campus research institute called Ordell Ugo. Establishing a congruent network of users who have similar food habits and possible linkage with the thinking abilities was the major project goal.

#### **Udacity Code Reviewer at Udacity**

July 2015 - December 2015 (6 months)

I am one of the very first Udacity Code Reviewers, where I review student project submissions. For each submission, I do both a thorough code review and project evaluation. I strive to give actionable and helpful feedback to students while also improving my code reviewing skills at the same time.

#### Student Ambassador at Google

August 2014 - November 2015 (1 year 4 months)

As part of the Google Student Ambassador Program, I was given opportunities to explore a different side of myself. I have been a part of many initiatives / pilot programs that Google launched to help students become better at what they do. One such activity was when the team here launched "Android Student Clubs". I was responsible to train students in Android and take to them to a stage where they could publish an application on the Play Store. I was responsible to take "Google India: Code to Learn" program to a couple of Colleges and Schools in Bangalore and helped drive participation. As part of the journey, I was given the opportunity to voice my opinion on the PMO App Contest that was launched in India [Link: https://youtu.be/Qw-885qODIc].

#### Mobile App Developer - Android / iOS at Boutline

May 2015 - July 2015 (3 months)

Was given the responsibility to implement backend functionality for their android application which was the first of it's kind messenger for sports-only discussion. Got the opportunity to learn iOS development through this internship and I also helped the same team with their iOS application as well.

## Software Research Intern at Unisys Global Services India

June 2014 - August 2014 (3 months)

I was given the task to implement and document adapters (dasein adapters) for integrating Unisys' Choreographer (Cloud offering by Unisys) with Verizon's Terremark Cloud Services.

#### Certifications

#### **Google for Education Basics**

Google April 2014

**Google Online Basics** 

Google April 2014

AdWords

Google December 2014 to December 2015

**Developing Android Apps** 

Udacity July 2015

Skills & Expertise

 $\mathbf{C}$ 

Java

C++

**Data Structures** 

**Android** 

HTML

**Algorithms** 

**CSS** 

**Programming** 

**Python** 

**JavaScript** 

**MySQL** 

**Android Application Developement** 

**OOP** 

Linux

**SQL** 

**PHP** 

**PowerPoint** 

**Machine Learning** 

**Data Mining** 

**JSON** 

**Representational State Transfer (REST)** 

Git

iOS Development

# Education

# PES Institute of Technology, Bangalore

Bachelor's degree, Information Science, 2012 - 2016

Activities and Societies: Ordell Ugo, Crucible of Research and Innovation (CORI)

# Sri Kumaran's Composite Pre University College

Department of Pre University Education, PCME, 2010 - 2012

# Sri Kumaran public school, Bangalore

Indian Certificate of Secondary Education (ICSE), Basic Schooling (Computer Science, Social Sciences,

Physics, Chemistry, Biology and Mathematics), 2002 - 2010

# Languages

# **English**

#### Honors and Awards

#### Pratibha Puraskara

Karnataka State Teacher's Association

June 2010

I was awarded 'Pratibha Puraskara' for my excellence in the field of music by the Karnataka State Teacher's Association.

#### **Publications**

# **Empirical Analysis of Social Networks**

Technical Research Organization India - 17th International Conference on Computer Science and Information Technology, Chennai (ICCIT 2016 - ISBN: 979-93-85225-62-8) April 10, 2016

Authors: Sujay Vittal, Lohit Ravindra

Today the world wide web is undergoing a subtle but profound shift to Web 2.0, to become more of a social web. The use of collaborative technologies such as blogs and social networking sites (SNS) leads to formation of instant online communities in which people communicate rapidly and conveniently with each other. This paper presents an empirical study of tweets obtained from Twitter. Our analysis reveals interesting references and provides a good visual representation of the same.

# **Projects**

# **Empirical Analysis of Social Networks**

August 2015 to December 2015

Members:Sujay Vittal, Lohit Ravindra

#### **Data Modelling for Effective Disaster Rehabilitation**

May 2016 to Present

Members: Sujay Vittal, Lohit Ravindra

Twitter's popularity as an information source has led to the development of applications and research in various domains. Humanitarian Assistance and Disaster Relief is one domain where information from Twitter is used to provide situational awareness during crisis. Researchers have used Twitter to predict the occurrence of earthquakes and identify relevant users to follow to obtain disaster related information. Studies of Twitter's use in disasters include regions such as China, and Chile. Similarly on November 8, 2015 to December 14, 2015 - The time when the entire subcontinent was taken aback, is majorly known as the South Indian floods. The disaster caused a lot of casualties, lot of loses. Disaster struck the city of Chennai in the most unexpected way. More than the impact that the floods left the people with, the aftermath of the disaster is something that haunts every person who was/was not a part of it even to this day. The major aim of this project is to enhance and strengthen the bridge between the relief organizations and the disaster victims.

This project uses twitter data obtained using Tweepy which again uses Streaming APIs to collect continuous stream of public information from Twitter. Twitter uses Open Authentication and each request must be signed with valid Twitter user credentials. Searching on Twitter is facilitated through the use of

parameters which include keywords, hashtags, phrases, geographic regions, and usernames or user IDs. The geographical details and relevant tweets have been mapped to construct heatmaps using Google Maps API. There are two major heat maps - one for weather data and other one for problems / tweets. This setup primarily proves to be at use only at the relief end. We also have developed a better communication bridge where the victims under impact can directly communicate with the right set of people - to seek help (food, clothes, basic amenities).

# **Sujay Vittal**

Developer Associate at SAP Labs India Pvt. Ltd.



# 1 person has recommended Sujay

"Sujay questions his tasks and finds out if it could be achieved in a simpler way, which is what i like about him. He is a quick learner. He worked with us as a mobile developer. He has good understanding about Android Backend and IOS Front End."

— Febin John James, Co-Founder, Boutline, managed Sujay at Boutline

Contact Sujay on LinkedIn